Irvin I. Rubin Papers
Irvin I. Rubin Papers
- Videotapes, Visual Learning, Inc.
  - Reinforced plastics lecture, by Gerald D. Shook, part 2, rubin_i_007; thermoplastics; part of Visual Plastics Learning series; reel-to-reel tape, 2 copies (Box 15)
  - Reinforced plastics lecture, by Gerald D. Shook, part 2, part of Visual Plastics Learning series; rubin_i_012; U-matic videocassette (Box 15)
    Processes outlined: hand layup, vacuum, spray up, matched metal die processes including preform, prepreg, Premix, SMC, Transfer filament winding, pultrusion, continuous casting, continuous laminating, hydroclave, pressure profcesses, injection molding.
- Writings
  - Special welding technique solves design problems in fabrication of polypropylene 'puspirator', 1961 (Box 16)
  - Plastics Technology articles, 1961 (Box 16)
  - Injection Molding Theory and Practice, 1969-1974; correspondence and book dust jacket (Box 16)
  - Injection Molding Theory and Practice corrections, 1974-1979; correspondence and notes about mistakes and corrections in book (Box 16)
  - Injection molding offprints, 1977; offprints of chapter 10 from Introduction to Polymer Science and Technology: An SPE Textbook; 2 clean, 1 annotated (Box 16)
  - Review of Plastics Process Engineering, 1979; carbon copy of review for publication in Polymer Letters and acknowledgment letter from H. Mark (Box 16)
  - It's time to reconsider hotrunner systems, part I, 1980; offprints from Plastics Engineering, vol 36: 2 (Box 16)
  - Mold cooling, 1981; from Advances in Plastics Technology vol 1, no. 1 (Box 16)
  - Handbook forms and guidelines, 1982-1989; guidelines for contributors for the Handbook of Plastics Materials and Technology (Box 16)
  - Handbook biographies and contracts, 1983-1989; materials related to author biographies and contracts for the Handbook of Plastics Materials and Technology (Box 16)
  - Injection molding article in Encyclopedia of Polymer Science and Engineering, 1986; correspondence with John Wiley & Sons, Publishers and offprint (Box 16)
  - Designing molds for injection molding, 1988; offprints, 1 clean and 1 annotated) (Box 16)
  - Injection molding typescript, 1988; 85-page typescript (Box 16)
  - Injection molding final correction, 1988 (Box 16)
  - Injection molding of thermoplastics, 1988-1991; correspondence with publisher, typescript and offprint of article published in SPI Plastics Engineering Handbook (Box 17)
  - Molds for injection molding, circa 1989; photocopy, 40 pp plus illustrations (Box 17)
  - SME video script, 1998; video script on plastics injection molding (Box 17)
  - Handbook PR materials, 1990s; marketing and publicity materials for Handbook of Plastics Technology and Materials (Box 17)
  - Bag ban articles, 2007; articles: "Bag ban is misguided solution," Plastics News; "San Francisco versus 1,000,000,000,000 plastic bags" (Box 17)
- Writings by others
  - Holtz, R.T., History of the product and market development of rigid vinyl materials, several pieces written for Plastics Pioneers' History and Artifacts Committee (Box 17)
- Artifact records
  - Artifact information sheets, undated; detailed information sheets filled out by Irvin I. Rubin about donated artifacts (Box 17)
  - Artifact inventory binder, undated; binder containing photographs and basic information about Rubin artifacts (Box 17)
  - Artifact photographs, undated; photographs of 103 Rubin artifacts; most are duplicates of the those in the binder (Box 17)